Preliminary Guide to the Craufurd D. W. Goodwin papers, 1960-2010 UA.29.02.0010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Craufurd D. W. Goodwin papers
1960-2010
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Goodwin, Craufurd D. W.
UA.29.02.0010
78 Linear Feet
Craufurd D. Goodwin has served as a Professor of Economics and administrator at Duke University since 1962. Papers of Craufurd D. W. Goodwin, educator and administrator at Duke University, include correspondence, writings, and subject files relating to his roles as Professor of Economics, Director of International Studies, Vice Provost and Director of International Programs, Vice Provost for Research, and Dean of the Graduate School. Also includes materials from his work for the Ford Foundation.
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Records, such as search committee files or others pertaining to employment where individuals are identified, are closed for 70 years.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Craufurd D. W. Goodwin papers were received by the University Archives from a variety of resources between 1985-1994. Accession (2009-0191) was added to the collection in September 2009. Accession (2009-0240) was added to the collection in November 2009. Accession UA2017-0030 was added to the collection in July 2017.
Biographical Note
Craufurd D. Goodwin has served as a Professor of Economics and administrator at Duke University since 1962. He was born on May 23, 1934 in Montreal, Canada. He earned a B. A. in Economics and Political Science from McGill University in 1955, and a Ph. D. in Economics from Duke University in 1958. He joined the faculty at Duke as a Professor of Economics in 1962. In addition to his teaching and research in economics, Goodwin has held a number of administrative positions at Duke University:
Chronology List
1962-1963 Assistant to the Provost
1963-1964 Secretary of the University; Assistant to the Provost
1964-1966 Secretary of the University; Assistant Provost
1966-1968 Assistant Provost; Director of International Studies
1968-1972 Vice Provost for International Studies
1971-1976 Program Officer in Charge, European and International Affairs, The Ford Foundation
1980-1987 Vice Provost for Research and Dean of the Graduate School
He has written and co-authored numerous books, most recently Economics and National Security: A History of Their Interaction (1991); Missing the Boat: The Failure to Internationalize American Higher Education (1991); Academic Mobility in a Changing World: Regional and Global Trends (ed. with A. Smith, U. Teichler and P. Blumenthal, 1996); Beyond Government: Extending the Public Policy Debate in Emerging Democracies (ed. with Michael Nacht, 1995); Talking to Themselves: The Search for Rights and Responsibilities of the Press and Mass Media in Four Latin American Nations (with Michael Nacht, 1995); The Academic's Handbook, 2nd Ed. (with Leigh DeNeef, 1995), and Art and the Market (1998).
He directs the Honors Program in the Department of Economics and is editor of the journal, History of Political Economy. He is currently the James B. Duke Professor of Economics and teaches introductory macroeconomics and microeconomics, as well as courses in the history of economic thought and policy.
Scope and Contents note
Papers of Craufurd D. W. Goodwin, educator and administrator at Duke University, include correspondence, writings, and subject files relating to his roles as Professor of Economics, Director of International Studies, Vice Provost and Director of International Programs, Vice Provost for Research, and Dean of the Graduate School. Also included are records of the Board of Trustees Executive Committee, the Academic Council, the Provost Group, numerous economic and economic history professional societies, and several philanthropic foundations, including the Ford Foundation.
- Container List
  - Administrative Council, 1965 (Box 1)
    Arrangement note
    Boxes 1-8: No accession info, material from 1960s. Boxes 9-10: Material received May 1, 1978. Boxes 11-12: A82-128. Boxes 13-14: A85-113. Boxes 15-21: A90-81. Boxes 22-25: A90-96. Boxes 26-29: A91-97. Box 30: A92-101. Boxes 31-32: A94-12. Box 33: A93-92 and A95-104. Box 34: A93-92. Boxes 35-36: A94-122.
  - International studies (Box 1)
  - Area studies (Box 1)
  - Institutional Advancement Office, 1964-1966 (Box 1)
  - University Calendar, reconsideration of (Box 1)
  - Provost Cole
    - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1)
  - Center for Southern Studies (Box 1)
  - Conference of Presidents of Methodist Universities, September 5-7, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Duke family research (Box 1)
  - Financial statements (Box 1)
  - Lilly Endowment (Box 1)
  - President Knight, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
  - Provost Group, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees
    - Executive Committee (Box 1)
  - Board minutes (Box 2)
  - UNESCO (Box 2)
  - Under-privileged, teachers of the (Box 2)
  - University seal, shield (Box 2)
  - Urban Studies, proposal for a program (Box 2)
  - Faculty work load study (Box 2)
  - Faculty abroad (Box 2)
  - Haviland, H. Field, Brookings Institute (Box 2)
  - International education (Box 2)
  - Ford Foundation
    - Campus Planning Study (Box 2)
    - Draft of submission (Box 2)
  - Graduate Affairs Committee (Box 2)
  - Guatemala trip (Box 2)
  - Hobbs (Box 2)
  - Hoover (Box 2)
  - IBM (Box 2)
  - Knight inauguration (Box 2)
  - Regional Education Laboratory Proposal (Box 2)
  - Provost communications (Box 2)
  - Tobacco, research on (Box 2)
  - Trustee lists and appointments (Box 3)
  - International studies (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation Program in International Teaching and Research, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Academic Council, 1962-1967 (Box 3)
  - Addressograph (Box 3)
  - Administrative Council, 1966-1969 (Box 3)
  - Admissions (Box 3)
  - African and Afro-American Studies (Box 3)
  - Alcoholic beverages on campus, Woman's College, 1967 (Box 4)
  - American Economic Association (Box 4)
  - Budget, 1966-1969 (Box 4)
  - Canadian Studies (Box 4)
  - COBRE (Committee on Basic Research in Education) (Box 4)
  - Consortium (Duke Univ., Univ. of Toronto, Univ. of London, Univ. of East Africa) (Box 4)
  - Continuing education (Box 4)
  - Education and world affairs, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Committee on University International Programs (Box 4)
  - Woman's College - Free Univ., Berlin, Scholarship exchange (Box 4)
  - Faculty analysis (Box 4)
  - Forestry School - Report for Trustees, 1968 (Box 4)
  - Hobbs, Marcus E., correspondence (Box 5)
  - International Association of Universities, Montreal, August 30-September 5, 1970 (Box 5)
  - International Honors Program (Box 5)
  - International studies (Box 5)
  - Academic averages (Box 5)
  - Academic Council, 1964-1966 (Box 5)
  - Administrative Committee (Box 5)
  - African Studies Program (Box 5)
  - American Men of Science (Box 5)
  - Associated Research Council, 1963-1965 (Box 5)
  - Babcock Foundation (Box 5)
  - Preliminary proposal for a Center for Analysis of Military Experience (Box 5)
  - Economics, Department of, 1963-1966 (Box 5)
  - Education and World Affairs (Box 5)
  - Educational administration (Box 5)
  - Educational Facilities Committee (Box 6)
  - Educational Goals Committee (Box 6)
  - EWA (Box 6)
  - Executive Committee, Board of Trustees, 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - International Students Advisory Committee (Box 6)
  - President Knight, correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 6)
  - Library (Box 6)
  - American Libraries and the Federal Government (Box 6)
  - Medical Education for Foreign Scholars in the Medical School (Box 7)
  - National Science Foundation Meeting, February 20-22, 1969 (Box 7)
  - Negro students at Duke University (Box 7)
  - Project Nicaragua (Box 7)
  - Peace Corps - International Studies (Box 7)
  - Provost Group, 1966-1969 (Box 7)
  - Report on Consideration of Black Studies at Duke University, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
  - Research Triangle Foundation (Box 7)
  - Snare, John L. (Box 7)
  - Southern Economic Association (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council, 1966-1969 (Box 7)
  - University Committee, Board of Trustees (Box 7)
  - University Committee, Board of Trustees (Box 8)
  - University Planning Committee (Box 8)
  - University Policy and Planning Advisory Committee (Box 8)
  - Winchester Excavation Project (Box 8)
  - Woodhall, Barnes (Box 8)
  - Trustee Committee for Institutional Advancement, 1967-1975 (Box 9)
  - Library Council, 1969-1974 (Box 9)
  - University Research Council, 1968-1975 (Box 9)
  - Board of Trustees Executive Committee, 1967-1972 CLOSED (Box 9)
  - Heaton, Herbert (Box 9)
  - Association for Canadian Studies in the United States [3 folders] (Box 10)
  - Commonwealth Studies (Box 10)
  - Economics Department (Box 10)
  - General correspondence [3 folders] (Box 10)
  - Subject files, Department of Economics, 1963-1981 (Box 11)
    - Absence of Decision… (Box 11)
    - NEH Grant Application Recommendations (Box 11)
    - Academic Council (Box 11)
    - Academic Senate (Box 11)
    - Economics 1, 2 (Box 11)
    - Duke University 50th Anniversary (Box 11)
    - Duke Comes of Age (Box 11)
    - Fund raising (Box 11)
    - Freshman advisory (Box 11)
    - History of Economics Society (Box 11)
    - Cooperative Program in the Humanities (Box 11)
    - Internal Development and Alumni Relations Council (Box 11)
    - North Carolina Mutual Life Insurance Company (Box 11)
    - Salmond, John A. (Box 11)
    - State of the Economy Seminar (Box 11)
    - Smith, John H. (Box 11)
    - Shell Foundation (Box 11)
    - Smith Richardson Foundation, Inc. (Box 11)
    - Symposium on the Roles of the University in a Post-Colonial World: Subcommittee (Box 11)
    - Trustee Committee on Institutional Advancement (Box 11)
    - United Nations Association (Box 11)
    - UNC-Chapel Hill - Duke University, Cooperative Arrangements (Box 11)
    - United Fund (Box 11)
  - National Science Foundation, 1969-1976 (Box 12)
  - American Council of Learned Societies (Box 13)
  - American Studies at foreign institutions (Box 13)
  - Report on American Studies (Box 13)
  - American Studies Abroad, with Particular Reference to the American Council of Learned Societies Program (Box 13)
  - The Development of National Book Resources. Canberra, Australia: AACOBS, 1965 (Box 14)
  - Inquiry into Research Activities and Proposals of Departments in the Social Sciences, 1967 (Box 14)
  - Bibliographies (Box 14)
  - Books Published in Translation and in English. U.S. Information Agency, 1962-1968. (Box 14)
  - A, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Abramovitz, Moses (Box 15)
  - American Economics Association (Box 15)
  - Australia (Box 15)
  - Australian Dictionary of Biography (Box 15)
  - B, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Bangert, Harold (Box 15)
  - Blackburn, John (Box 15)
  - Brookings, Exhortation and controls - reviews (Box 15)
  - Brookings, Wage price study (Box 15)
  - C, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Canadian Economics Association (Box 15)
  - Canadian Studies, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Coleberd, Bob (Box 15)
  - Bicentennial Conference - Economic Consequences (Box 15)
  - Conference for the Study of Political Thought (Box 15)
  - Conference - Keynes Western Ontario (Box 15)
  - Conference - Economics Profession, 1974 (Box 15)
  - Council of Graduate Schools, 1982 (Box 15)
  - D, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Davidson, C. Girard (Box 15)
  - Dobrovnik papers (Box 15)
  - Duke History of Economy Group (Box 15)
  - E, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Eastern Economic Association (Box 15)
  - Eastern Sociological Society meeting (Box 15)
  - Energy project, Expense vouchers (Box 15)
  - Energy policy, Book reviews (Box 15)
  - Economic History Association (Box 15)
  - Economic policy proposal (Box 15)
  - Economic policy, 1981 (Box 15)
  - Economics meeting, Ford Foundation (Box 15)
  - Emory University Lecture (Box 15)
  - Epoch campaign: Foundation committee (Box 15)
  - F, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Faculty Advisory System Supervisory Committee (Box 15)
  - Faculty Benefits Handbook (Box 15)
  - Faculty data (Box 15)
  - Faculty, pre-1981 (Box 15)
  - Faculty newsletter (Box 15)
  - Faculty re-definition (Box 16)
  - Faculty - Trustee Liaison Committee (Box 16)
  - Forbes, Kit (Box 16)
  - Frolines, J. A. (Box 16)
  - Foreign Policy Institute (Box 16)
  - Fulbright-Hays Program (Box 16)
  - G, pre-1980 (Box 16)
  - Graduate students, pre-1981 - files separated (Box 16)
  - H, pre-1981 (Box 16)
  - History of Economics Society, 1978-1979
    - Meeting, 1981 (Box 16)
    - Presidential Address, 1979 (Box 16)
    - Executive Meeting, 1979 (Box 16)
  - Humanities Seminar, Summer 1971 (Box 16)
  - I, pre-1980 (Box 16)
  - International Educational Exchange (Box 16)
  - IIE - Springhill Conference (Box 16)
  - International Studies, Duke Center for, pre-1980 (Box 16)
  - J, pre-1980 (Box 16)
  - Jones Foundation, W. Alton (Box 16)
  - Journals (Box 16)
  - K, pre-1981 (Box 16)
  - Kruzel, Joseph (Box 16)
  - L, pre-1981 (Box 16)
  - Library, pre-1980 (Box 16)
  - Library Council (Box 16)
  - Long Range Planning Committee (Box 16)
  - M, pre-1980 (Box 16)
  - Mc, pre-1981 (Box 16)
  - Mansergh, Nicholas (Box 16)
  - Material Support, pre-1975 (Box 16)
  - Medieval and Renaissance Studies (Box 16)
  - Media, FACS/NBC Conference (Box 17)
  - Murray, Dame Rosemary (Box 17)
  - Midway College lecture (Box 17)
  - N, pre-1981 (Box 17)
  - National Council on Foreign Language and International Studies, National Targets Project (Box 17)
  - Neil, Charles RESTRICTED (Box 17)
  - Nixon Library (Box 17)
  - North Carolina College at Durham (Box 17)
  - North Carolina Press Association (Box 17)
  - O, pre-1981 (Box 17)
  - Overseas Foreign Language and Area Studies (Box 17)
  - P, pre-1981 (Box 17)
  - Pacific Studies (Box 17)
  - Package - The Economics in Presidential Policy Making (Box 17)
  - Partridge, Percy (Box 17)
  - Patent Policy Committee (Box 17)
  - Perlman, Mark (Box 17)
  - Personal correspondence, pre-1981 (Box 17)
  - Personnel (Box 17)
  - Petridis, Anastasios (Ray) RESTRICTED (Box 17)
  - Phi Beta Kappa (Box 17)
  - Place of the Citizen in U.S. Foreign Policy Making (Box 17)
  - Presidential luncheons (Box 17)
  - Preston, Richard A. (Box 17)
  - Public Policy and Management Program for Case/Course Development - Harvard (Box 17)
  - R, pre-1981 (Box 17)
  - Registrar's statistics (Box 17)
  - S (Box 17)
  - Science and Public Affairs, Round Table on (Box 17)
  - Science Society and Human Values (Box 17)
  - Smithsonian Institution (Box 18)
  - Speeches (Box 18)
  - Spengler (Box 18)
  - State Department (Box 18)
  - Study Abroad, Committee on (Box 18)
  - T, pre-1981 (Box 18)
  - Tenure (Box 18)
  - TIAA/CREF (Box 18)
  - Trends and Perspective, Committee on (Box 18)
  - Trade Policy Research Center (Box 18)
  - Traveling expense vouchers (Box 18)
  - Truman Library Institute (Box 18)
  - Trustee Nomination Committee (Box 18)
  - Trustee material, U. M. Upchurch (Box 18)
  - Tuition Loan Program (Box 18)
  - U (Box 18)
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council, 1966 (Box 18)
  - Undergraduate Research Assistantship Program (Box 18)
  - U.S. Chamber of Commerce, Council on Trends (Box 18)
  - U.S. Chamber of Commerce paper (Box 18)
  - United Nations (Box 18)
  - United Nations University (Box 18)
  - University Loan Committee (Box 18)
  - University Marshall (Box 18)
  - University Planning Committee (Box 18)
  - V, pre-1981 (Box 18)
  - Vanderbilt, Valley Authority Idea (Box 18)
  - Vanderbilt visit (Box 18)
  - W, pre-1981 (Box 18)
  - Woman's College (Box 18)
  - XYZ, pre-1981 (Box 18)
  - Year round operation (Box 18)
  - NSF Papers [7 folders] (Box 19)
  - Carnegie and Commonwealth Publication Fund (Box 19)
  - Publications Committee (Box 19)
  - AIESEC - Duke (Box 19)
  - Alumni Affairs (Box 19)
  - American Council on Education (Box 19)
  - Angier B. Duke Scholarships (Box 19)
  - Appointments Office (Box 19)
  - Archives (Box 19)
  - Associated Research Council (Box 19)
  - Babcock Foundation, Mary Reynolds (Box 19)
  - Budget planning, 1969-1970 (Box 19)
  - Calendar of the Colleges (Box 19)
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 19)
  - Chariman of Departments, Director of Undergraduate Studies, Director of Graduate Studies (Box 19)
  - Cleaveland, Frederic N., Provost (Box 19)
  - Cole correspondence, 1967-1972 (Box 19)
  - Commencement (Box 19)
  - Corporate foundations (Box 19)
  - Counseling Center (Box 19)
  - Dag Hammaskjold College (Box 20)
  - Deferred tuition plan (Box 20)
  - Di Bona, Joseph (Box 20)
  - Disruption plan (Box 20)
  - Distinguished Professor Seminars (Box 20)
  - Duke Endowment (Box 20)
  - Educom (Box 20)
  - Education and world affairs (Box 20)
  - Educational Administration Advisory Group [5 folders] (Box 20)
  - Educational Facilities Committee (Box 20)
  - Enrollments (Box 20)
  - Emeritus for employment, 1965 (Box 20)
  - Fellowships, Post-doctoral academic (Box 20)
  - Fallout preparedness (Box 20)
  - Financial aid (Box 20)
  - Founder's Day (Box 20)
  - Fraternities (Box 20)
  - Friday Luncheon Club (Box 20)
  - Pickets and protests (Box 20)
  - Provost Group [4 folders] (Box 20)
  - Economic Thought and Public Policy (Box 20)
  - Europe, More Muscle than Mind? (Box 20)
  - Europe's Malaise (Box 20)
  - History of Economics Textbook (Box 20)
  - Goodwin - Book Review, 1979
    - American Dollars - Canadian Prosperity (Box 20)
    - Reflections of an Economic Policy Maker (Box 20)
    - Eastern Sociological Society (Box 20)
    - Fiscal Responsibility in Constitutional Democracy (Box 20)
    - Economic Advice and Economic Policy (Box 20)
    - Ethics and Society in England (Box 20)
  - AEA Session, 1978 (Box 20)
  - National Economic Planning (Box 20)
  - Kyklos (Box 20)
  - Brookings B.U. conference (Box 20)
  - Adam Smith - Bicentennial (Box 20)
  - Boston Conference, Report on (Box 20)
  - Review: Planning for Development (Box 20)
  - Wage - Price Policy Introduction (Box 20)
  - International Economic Images (Box 20)
  - Image of Australia Index, 1973 (Box 20)
  - Marginal Revolution in Economics, The (Box 20)
  - Economic Analysis in National Perspective (Box 20)
  - Review: The First Industrial Revolution (Box 20)
  - Review: John Rae Political Economist (Box 20)
  - Reviews: Image of Australia (Box 20)
  - Economic Development and Cultural Change (Box 20)
  - Current History Article, 1967 (Box 20)
  - Introduction to a Decade of the Commonwealth (Box 20)
  - Forgotten Forerunner of Social Credit - William Alexander Thompson (Box 20)
  - Student exchange (Box 20)
  - Review: The Fulbright Program (Box 20)
  - Economic Dimensions of the Commonwealth, Galleys (Box 20)
  - History of Economic Thought to freshmen (Box 20)
  - Economic Enquiry in Australia - Forward (Box 21)
  - Institutionalism in African Economic Thought (Box 21)
  - Institutionalism in Gold Coast Political and Economic Thought (Box 21)
  - Irwin text (Box 21)
  - Jamaica (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous, pre-1971 (Box 21)
  - Musgrave, Anthony - Studies in Political Economy (Box 21)
  - Review: Career Service - History of Personnel Administration… (Box 21)
  - London (Box 21)
  - The Making of Economic Policy, Remarks To Social Studies Teachers, 1991 (Box 21)
  - On Breaking Bad Habits, Remarks to Duke Emeriti (Box 21)
  - The Transfer of Economic Ideas in the Commonwealth (Box 21)
  - Working papers - Transfer volume (Box 21)
  - Economic Ideas in the Development of Jamaica (Box 21)
  - Transfer of ideas (Box 21)
  - Schneider, Fred D. - The Imperial Factor in Canadian External Policy (Box 21)
  - Evolution of the Commonwealth (Box 21)
  - Miscellaneous applications for fellowships, 1967-1968 (Box 21)
  - Review: Safarian, Foreign Ownership of Canadian Industry (Box 21)
  - Wall Street Journal - Foreign Students Still Flock To U.S. (Box 21)
  - Economic Scientists and Economic Policy, Some Reflections
    - HES Meeting, 1982 (Box 21)
  - Canada at a Century (Box 21)
  - Reader's Digests Almanac, pre-1969 (Box 21)
  - Reprint list, pre-1971 (Box 21)
  - Reviews, pre-1979 (Box 21)
  - Ford Foundation - Request for Continuation of Support for International Studies at Duke University, 1969 (Box 21)
  - Ford Foundation - General European and Canadian research (Box 21)
  - Ford Foundation - International Economics Comp. (Box 21)
  - Truman Project (Box 22)
  - Truman Centennial Manuscript (Box 22)
  - Talk to NASFA (Box 22)
  - Talk: Academic and Professional Decay (Box 22)
  - Decay - General (Box 22)
  - Prevention of Decay (Box 22)
  - IIE (Box 22)
  - Coats, Miscellaneous correspondence, 1981-1984 (Box 22)
  - Channing (Box 22)
  - Lange - Wage Regulation paper (Box 22)
  - International Education Act (Box 22)
  - Commonwealth Studies Center Reports, 1962-1967 (Box 22)
  - Search Division of International Studies (Box 22)
  - Bates - Ford/Olin proposals (Box 22)
  - Hope/Books/Publications correspondence (Box 22)
  - Grants/funding general (Box 22)
  - General correspondence (Box 22)
  - Economics Department, administrative correspondence (Box 22)
  - Menger/Morgenstern/Library Donations (Box 22)
  - Correspondence - Dean of Graduate School, 1970-1986 [3 folders] (Box 23)
  - Inter-University Committee on Travel Grants (Box 23)
  - Health, Education and Welfare, Department of (Box 23)
  - History Review Committee (Box 23)
  - Testimony before U.S. House of Representatives, 1985 (Box 23)
  - Congressional testimony, notes and papers (Box 23)
  - History of Economic Thought - Hope, 1982-1985 (Box 23)
  - Wellesley II (Box 23)
  - International Research and Exchanges Board (Box 23)
  - Research Unit (Box 23)
  - Menger Conference - Faculty and graduate students attending, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Miscellaneous papers - Foundations; Ford, Donner, Hazan (Box 23)
  - Presidential search letters - offering consideration (Box 23)
  - Okun, Robert (Box 23)
  - Woodrow Wilson Conference, 1989 (Box 23)
  - Economics Dept., 1967-1969 (Box 24)
  - Research Council, 1963-1968 (Box 24)
  - International Office, 1966-1973
    - Budget (Box 24)
    - Financial statement (Box 24)
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica (Box 24)
  - Thomson, William Alexander - Dictionary of Canadian Biography (Box 24)
  - British Economists and Australian Gold (Box 24)
  - British Economic Image of Australia (Box 24)
  - By Filtered Light: British Views of the Australian Economy (Box 24)
  - Economic Theory and Society: A Plea for Process Analysis (Box 24)
  - Chapter 9: The Utopia of Practical Economists (Box 24)
  - Economic Development and Empire: Depressions, Resources, and Race - International Economic (Box 24)
  - History Conference (Box 24)
  - Mansergh volume (Box 24)
  - British Economic Theories of Empire, 1850-1950 (Box 24)
  - U.S. Chamber of Commerce Paper on Economic Planning (Box 24)
  - Planning material (Box 24)
  - Proposal for a program of training and research in International Affairs (Box 24)
  - Soviet-Chinese Conflict and Its Repercussions, 1964 (Box 24)
  - Book review: New Directions in Economic Policy (Box 25)
  - Philosophy of Science (Box 25)
  - Sub-disciplines session (Box 25)
  - History of Living Economist (Box 25)
  - Classical economics (Box 25)
  - Marginal economics session (Box 25)
  - History of Capital Theory (Box 25)
  - Resources for teaching and research (Box 25)
  - Review of Sowell (Box 25)
  - Session of contributed papers (Box 25)